考虑一个相当标准的工业机器人，有6个旋转接头试图添加一个
Consider a fairly standard industrial robot with 6 rotational joints. Trying to add a
在链接零上坐标框架并在链接6上添加一个坐标框架
coordinate frame on link zero and going to add a coordinate frame on link 6 which is
末端执行器框架实际完成工作的机器人的位。我们谈了
the end-effector frame the bit of the robot that actually does the work. And we talked
关于运动模型，其关于框架6的姿态与框架零和
about kinematic models which relate the pose of frame 6 with respect to frame zero and
它是机器人第6关节角度的函数。现在让我们说这个机器人存在
it's a function of the 6th joint angles of the robot. Let's say now that this robot exists
在工厂里，工厂有自己的世界坐标框架。
in a factory and the factory is got its own world coordinate frame indicated over here.
并且我们知道机器人的姿势相对于世界坐标系的零点。
And we know the pose of the robot link zero with respect to the world coordinate frame.
我们称之为机器人的基本变换。机器人末端执行器的姿势
We called this the base transform of the robot. The pose of the robots end effector in the
简单地通过复合基础变换就可以获得世界坐标系
world coordinate frame can be attained for it's simply by compounding the base transform
通过机器人的正向运动变换，这是机器人关节角度的函数。
with the forward kinematic transform of the robot which is a function of the robot's joint angles.
想象一下，我现在介绍了另一个机器人，这个机器人从屋顶倒挂
Imagine now that I introduced another robot, this one's hanging upside down from the roof
并且我们知道它相对于世界坐标系的姿势然后我们可以写一个
and we know its pose with respect to the world coordinate frame then we can write an
表达第二个机器人相对于世界的末端效应器姿势。
expression for the end-effector pose of the second robot with respect to the world.
现在，让我们看一下机器人的工具端。运动学为我们提供了机器人的姿势
Now, let's look at the tool end of the robot. The kinematics give us the pose of the robots
末端执行器，但通常它确实给我们一些安装法兰的姿势
end effector but typically it actually does gives us the pose of some mounting flange
在机器人的末端，我们想为此加上某种工具。所以，我们
on the end of the robot and we would like to affix some sort of tool to that. So, we
这里要介绍工具，这是机器人的某种磨具
are going to introduce the tool here, this is some kind of grinding tool that the robot
正在携带。当然，我们对这个特定工具的业务端感兴趣。
is carrying. And of course, we're interested in the business end of this particular tool.
我们想知道这个坐标系的姿势。通过一些仔细的测量，
We want to know the pose of this coordinate frame here. In with some careful measurement,
我们可以确定从第6帧到第E帧的相对姿势，这将是恒定的相对姿势。
we can determine the relative pose from the frame 6 to frame E and this would be constant relative pose.
那么，现在关于世界坐标系的末端效应器的姿势可以
So, now the pose of the end-effector, with respect to the world coordinate frame, can
由这组复合姿势写成。它是基础变换的复合体
be written by this set of compounded poses. It's the base transform compounded with the
臂的运动学模型与安装的恒定工具变换相结合
kinematic model of the arm compounded with the constant tool transform from the mounting
指向该工具的业务端。
point to the business end of the tool.
这是我们以前的MATLAB会议之一，我们正在使用的模型
Here's one of our previous MATLAB sessions where we were working with a model of the
Puma-560机器人。我们可以在Denavit-Hartenberg参数表下看到
Puma-560 robot. We can see here under the table of the Denavit-Hartenberg parameters
有一个基本变换矩阵和一个工具变换矩阵，它们各自对应
that there is a base transform matrix and a tool transform matrix and each of them corresponds
零转和零转换。但我们可以轻松改变基础变换
to zero rotation and zero translation. But we can easily change the base transform of
例如，通过调整串行链接机器人对象的基本属性来实现机器人。
the robot for instance by adjusting the base property of the serial link robot object.
所以，我可能会改变基本变换的平移路径。也许，我会放置
So, I might change the translational path of the base transform. Perhaps, I will place
机器人在X方向10米，Y方向15米，也许
the robot at 10 meters in the X direction and 15 meters in the Y direction and maybe
我会把它抬高一点，或者沿Z方向向上移动两米。所以，现在
I will put it up a little bit higher or move it up two meters in the Z direction. So, now
机器人对象有一个我们找到的不同的基础变换。
the robot object has got a different base transform that we find.
现在，计算机器人的正向运动学，这被考虑在内，我们可以
Now, compute the forward kinematics of the robot, this is taken into account and we can
看到现在的末端效应器位置是完全不同的。基础变换非常好
see that the end-effector position now is quite different. The base transform is a very
强大的功能，我可以设置一个更复杂的基础变换。例如，我实际上可以
powerful function and I could set a more complex base transform. For instance, I could actually
将机器人颠倒过来，我将围绕x轴旋转pi弧度
turn the robot upside down and I am going to rotate it around the x-axis by pi radians
所以这就是机器人基础变换现在的样子，如果我再次计算前进
so this is what the robot base transform looks like now and if I again compute the forward
对于同一组关节角度的运动学，我们将看到机器人末端执行器的位置
kinematics for that same set joint angles, we'll see that the position of the robot end-effector
是不同的，我们可以看到末端执行器的方向是非常不同的
is different and we can see that the orientation of the end-effector is very different the
旋转子矩阵中的正号和负号位于不同的位置。所以，
positive and minus signs in the rotations sub matrix are in different locations. So,
我已经有效地移动了机器人并将其颠倒过来，这非常容易
I have effectively moved the robot and turn it upside down and that's very very easy to
做这个基础变换的概念。
do with this concept of a base transform.
我可能想对机器人做的另一件事是向它添加工具变换
The other thing that I might want to do to the robot is to add a tool transform to it
并通过调整工具属性来做到这一点，我可能会声明该工具已经获得
and do that by adjusting the tool property and I might declare that the tool has got
x方向的偏移为零，Y方向的偏移为零，可能为0.2米
an offset of zero in the x direction, zero in the Y direction and perhaps it's 0.2 meters
在Z方向上指向机器人末端的安装板。
in the Z direction which is pointing out of the mounting plate on the end of the robot.
现在，您可以看到工具变换代表有限位移。现在，
And now, you can see that the tool transform represents a finite displacement. And now,
如果我要计算那组特定关节角度的正向运动学，我们会
if I'm going to compute the forward kinematics for that particular set of joint angles, we'll
看到末端效应器的位置略有不同，因为现在它正在使用这个工具
see that the end-effector position is slightly different because now it's taking this tool
转化为计数。
transform into a count.